# Abhijit Hoskeri - Resume

abhijithoskeri@gmail.com (408) 680 6041

# **Objective**

To perform challenging work that will utilize my technical and analytical skill on the Linux/Unix platform to create useful applications and technology.

# **Summary**

I have been working for over 6 years. Currently I am working on virtualization and storage optimization applications. Before this I have worked on the development and maintenance of the deepOfix Mail Server, a Linux distribution meant to run email servers.

#### **Technical Skills**

### **Programming Languages**

C, Perl, Python, Ruby, Scheme

### **Development**

- Knowledge of UNIX system programming (System calls, basic library functions, networking, etc)
- Linux kernel filesystems (ext2 and ext3) and device-mapper (dm) driver internals.
- Excellent understanding of the UNIX and Linux ecosystem
  - Excellent knowledge of Bash scripting and automation.
  - o Experience with installation and maintainence of Email server infrastructure.
  - o Linux firewall, VPN and router configuration.
- Development of distributed server applications with python.
- ORM (Object-Relation Mapping) frameworks like Storm.
- Experience with the MVC (Model-View-Controller) model of application development (Django, Sinatra).
- Packaging software and maintenance of such packages. (Debian and RPM packages)

#### **Tools**

- Version control systems including Git, Mercurial, Subversion, CVS.
- Project management with Trac, Bugzilla, Request-Tracker, Jira, etc.

# **Work Experience**

### Atlantis Computing Pvt. Ltd. (Aug 2008 till present)

- Worked on development of a deduplicating filesystem based on ext2/ext3 kernel module in Linux. The ext2 filesystem
  was modified to perform deduplication of incoming data to eliminate redundant block writes and improve performance
  of virtual machines by 500%.
- Development of features and bug fixing on 'Atlantis ILIO', which is a distributed server application to manage and enhance the performance of virtual machine disk images. This product is implemented in python.
- Worked on converting ILIO from a centralized architecture to a distributed architecture to support larger scale of users and workload.
- Built a Linux live-cd based installer for ILIO. This involved development of modules for setting up VMware ESX
  server and configuration of virtual machines and applications. The installer was built as a python application which itself
  ran on a virtual machine.
- Wrote a Windows MFC application to monitor and report health of Virtual Machines. This application runs on user virtual machines and responds to commands sent over a TCP/IP socket.
- Implemented a high availability solution for failover of services provided by ILIO using heartbeat, DRBD (Distributed Replicated Block Device) and OCFS2 (Oracle Clustered File System)

#### DeepRoot Linux Private Limited. (Sep 2006 to July 2008)

- Development and maintenance of the deepOfix Mail Server, a GNU/Linux distribution built to run email services.
- Rebuilt the entire installer and package set to make the entire system more manageable and upgradable.
- Fixed bugs and added features to various open source software used by the product, and contributed them up-stream.
- Headed the support team, comprising four people to provide incident support and customizations for the above product and allied services. Responsible for over 200 servers in my support role.
- Wrote patches for internal use for software such as Qmail, Dovecot, etc.
- Designed and comissioned custom email server architectures as per requirements of customers.

#### Maspro IT Solutions Private Limited (Dec 2005 to Aug 2006)

- Worked as an on-site engineer performing Systems Administration tasks, first at EthicSoft, Jayanagar in Bangalore and then at Resolve India, a division of Tally Solutions.
- At EthicSoft, was responsible for the corporate LAN, including email services, firewalls, and the test servers for various projects at the company.
- Implemented a version control system using CVS. Created an automated commit-compile-build-deploy system on the above test servers. Consulted on development of a firewall/gateway security appliance for one of the projects at EthicSoft.
- At Resolve India, I was responsible for the maintenance of the LAN, Windows based terminal servers, firewall, email servers etc, as a Systems Administrator.

## **Education Background**

- B.E. in Industrial and Production Engineering, from Basaveshwara Engg. College, Bagalkot, Karnataka in 2005.
- Six month course in 'Advanced Unix Programming' at Uttara, Bangalore